Guide to the Velvet Underground Collection, 1964-2015.
Velvet Underground Collection,
- Recordings, 1965-2012
  - CDs, 1988-2009
    - Bootleg/Unofficially-released CDs, 1989-2007
      - The Velvet Underground. "After the White Heat." Nothing Songs Limited, 2006; CD-2694-2696 (Box 25)
      - The Velvet Underground. "At the Andy Warhol Museum.", Undated; CD-2697 (Box 25)
      - The Velvet Underground. "At The Factory. Warhole Tapes - Complete at the Andy Warhol Museum." Nothing Songs Limited, 2005; CD-2698-2699 (Box 25)
      - The Velvet Underground. "Boston Tea Party 1969." Scorpio Records., Undated; CD-2700-2703 (Box 25)
      - The Velvet Underground. "The Complete End Cole Ave. 2006 Remastered / Live at Max's Kansas City - The First Night." Nothing Songs Limited, 2006; CD-2704-2709 (Box 25)
      - The Velvet Underground. "Dispatches from the Dream Factory." Scorpio Records., Undated; CD-2710-2712 (Box 25)
      - The Velvet Underground. "European Tour 1993 - The Playhouse." Nothing Songs, 2007; CD-2713-2714 (Box 25)
      - The Velvet Underground. "European Tour 1993 - The Playhouse." Nothing Songs, 2007; CD-2715-2716 (Box 25)
      - The Velvet Underground. "The First Night." Aulica A.2151., Undated; CD-2717-2718 (Box 25)
      - The Velvet Underground. "Flowers of Evil.", Undated; CD-2719-2720 (Box 25)
      - The Velvet Underground. "La Cave 1968 - Problems in Urban Living.", Undated; CD-2721 (Box 25)
      - The Velvet Underground. "Live at End Cole Ave." Aulica 111.12 * NE/3. Live at End Cole Ave, Dallas, October 1969, Undated; CD-2725-2726 (Box 25)
      - The Velvet Underground. "The Legendary Guitar Amp Tapes 2006 Remastered" [sic]. Nothing Songs Limited, 2006; CD-2722-2724 (Box 26)
      - The Velvet Underground. "Ostrich / Hilltop." World Wide Records., Undated; CD-2727 (Box 26)
      - The Velvet Underground. "Ultimate Stereo Album - The Rare Mixies Collection of the Velvet Underground." Nothing Songs Limited, 2006; CD-2728-2731 (Box 26)
      - The Velvet Underground. "Ultra Rare Trax Vol. 4." 3D-Reality Classics., Undated; CD-2732 (Box 26)
      - The Velvet Underground. "Underground Music 1993.", Undated; CD-2733-2734 (Box 26)
      - The Velvet Underground. "Velvet Underground in Concert '69: A Tribute to Andy and Nico." Planet Sound Studios, 1989; CD-2735 (Box 26)
      - The Velvet Underground. "With Us From The Past." The Flying Tigers, 1993; CD-2736-2737 (Box 26)
      - The Velvet Underground and Nico. "Live in Columbus 1966 - Part One." Mind the Magic 032., Undated; CD-2741 (Box 26)
      - The Velvet Underground and Nico. "Live in Columbus 1966 - Part Two." Mind the Magic 032., Undated; CD-2742 (Box 26)
      - The Velvet Underground and Nico." Ultimate Mono and Acetates Album." Nothing Songs Limited, 2005; CD-2743-2745 (Box 26)
    - Rare CDRs, 1998-2002
      - The Velvet Underground. "Acetates #1.", Undated; CD-2746 (Box 26)
      - The Velvet Underground. "Berlin." December 14, 2006., Undated; CD-2747 (Box 26)
      - The Velvet Underground. "Boston Tea Party 1968.", Undated; CD-2748 (Box 26)
      - The Velvet Underground. "Covers and Oddities.", Undated; CD-2749 (Box 26)
      - The Velvet Underground. "Doug Yule Acetates.", Undated; CD-2750 (Box 26)
      - The Velvet Underground. "Hilltop Pop Festival 8-2-69 + Second Fret.", October 7, 1998; CD-2751 (Box 26)
      - The Velvet Underground. "Live at Second Fret - May 1970.", October 8, 1998; CD-2752 (Box 26)
      - The Velvet Underground. "March 4, 1971 Pt 3 63:36", Undated; CD-2753 (Box 26)
      - The Velvet Underground. "Matrix SF Late November 26 & 27, 1969 Snippets.", Undated; CD-2754-2755 (Box 26)
      - The Velvet Underground. "Moe's Acetates.", Undated; CD-2756-2758 (Box 26)
      - The Velvet Underground. "Velvets 4/66 'Heroin.'", Undated; CD-2759 (Box 26)
      - The Velvet Underground. "Velvet @ Max's." Penguin Recording, 2002; CD-2760 (Box 26)
      - The Velvet Underground. "Velvet Rehearsal (Set 1B)." Penguin Recording, 2002; CD-2761 (Box 26)
      - The Velvet Underground. "Velvet Underground @ Max's 8/23/70." Penguin Recording, 2002; CD-2762 (Box 26)
      - The Velvet Underground. "Velvet Underground Acetate." April 25, 1966., Undated; CD-2763 (Box 26)
      - The Velvet Underground. "Velvet Underground Acetate LP - Professor Norman Dohph", Undated; CD-2764 (Box 26)
  - Video/DVDs, Undated
    - "Vinyl: The Velvet Underground & Nico." Booklet and Video. Minerva Pictures, 2004., Undated; DVD-1691 (Box 27)
- Exhibition and Book Materials, 1983-2010; Kugelberg, Johan
  This series contains copies of material used in the creation of the book c/o The Velvet Underground, New York, NY or relate to a series of exhibitions of Velvet Underground materials including one at the Boo Hooray Gallery.
  - Concert List and Timeline, 1963-2008, Undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Velvet Underground Complete Timeline by Sal Mercuri, 2008 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - "The Velvet Underground Story" Miscellany, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - "Uptight: The Velvet Underground Story" Typescript Photocopy, with copy of Letter from Gerard Malanga to Sterling Morrison, Undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
    Photocopy of complete typescript of book by Bockris and Malanga, 218 p., plus photocopy of Morrison’s comments on the text, 57 p. Also included is a photocopy of an original typed cover letter signed by Malanga to Sterl[ing Morrison] dated February 23, 1983, a photocopy of a typed response letter signed by Morrison to Malanga dated Mar. 10, 1983, and 5 photocopied newspaper and magazine clippings.
  - "The Velvet Underground and Nico" Forced Exposure Interview Photocopy and Word Doc Printout, Undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
    Original dated Summer 1985
  - Inventory of Time Capsule 11 - Crozier Fine Art Warehouse, NYC, July 10, 1992-July 17, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - "All Tomorrow's Parties: Remembering the Velvet Underground" - Andy Warhol Museum Exhibit - Correspondence, Press, Slides, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Robin Hough Quote on VU, Sent to Sal - Photocopy, November 6, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - "c/o The Velvet Underground, New York, N.Y." Folders and press release., April 12, 2007-May 12, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    Press release for the exhibit “c/o The Velvet Underground, New York, N.Y.” at John McWhinnie @ Glenn Horowitz Bookseller, Apr. 12-May 12, 2007. Two copies. Empty printed folder, with Ectoplasm logo on back.
  - "c/o The Velvet Underground, New York, N.Y." Invitations., April 12, 2007-May 12, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    Sealed, folded handbill for the exhibit “c/o The Velvet Underground, New York, N.Y.” at John McWhinnie @ Glenn Horowitz Bookseller, New York, Apr. 12-May 12, 2007. 15 copies.
  - Megaplaten and CD Beurs Poster - Utrecht Collector's Fair, November 21, 2009-November 22, 2009 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    Poster for the 2009 Utrecht record fair, with announcement for a talk by Johan Kugelberg on the Velvet Underground.
  - "Verzamelaars Jaarbeurs" - Program from Utrecht Collector's Fair, November 21, 2009-November 22, 2009 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    “Verzamelaars Jaarbeurs.” Program from the 2009 Utrecht collector’s fair (organized in conjunction with the record fair), with an article on Johan Kugelberg and the Velvet Underground. 2 copies.
  - New York Public Library Exhibit Labels and Audience Questions, 2007, 2009 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    Ca. 104 exhibit labels, many with extensive narrative text, from Velvet Underground exhibits curated by Johan Kugelberg at Glenn Horowitz @ John McWhinnie Bookseller, New York (2007) and Hysteric Glamour, Tokyo (2009). 43 manuscript audience questions for Lou Reed, Moe Tucker, and Doug Yule, from the Velvet Underground panel discussion at the New York Public Library, Dec. 8, 2009. “Reserved seat” signs for Lou Reed, Moe Tucker, Doug Yule, and Johan Kugelberg from the Velvet Underground panel discussion at the New York Public Library, Dec. 8, 2009.
  - Johan Kugelberg Book Signing Flier, November 24, 2009 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    Flier for Johan Kugelberg book signing at Stand Out Records/Minus Zero records, London, Nov. 24, [2009]. With “Today!!” added in ms. at top.
  - Prospectus for The Velvet Underground, Edited by Johan Kugelberg, New York: Rizzoli, 2009 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    Prospectus for The Velvet Underground, edited by Johan Kugelberg. New York: Rizzoli, [2009]. 4 p. color prospectus for the book published as The Velvet Underground: New York Art.
  - Proof pages torn from "The Velvet Underground: New York Art" Edited by Johan Kugelberg., 2009 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    Digitized.
  - Proofs for the cover of "The Velvet Underground: New York Art" Edited by Johan Kugelberg, 2009 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Printed pages of materials used for "The Velvet Underground: New York Art" Edited by Johan Kugelberg (mostly digitized), 2009; CD-2573-2603 (Box 18)
  - Printed pages of materials used for "The Velvet Underground: New York Art" Edited by Johan Kugelberg (mostly digitized), 2009; CD-2573-2603 (Box 19)
  - Printed pages of materials used for "The Velvet Underground: New York Art" Edited by Johan Kugelberg (mostly digitized), 2009; CD-2573-2603 (Box 20, Folder 1-3)
  - "The New York Art of the Velvet Underground" at Hysteric Glamour Publicity, June 10, 2010 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    Postcard handbill for the exhibit “The New York Art of the Velvet Underground.” at Hysteric Glamour Shibuya, Tokyo, June 10, 2010.
  - 3 Silkscreen prints of Andy's Warhol's Exploding Plastic Inevitable with Nico and the Velvet Underground, 2007 (Box 17, Folder 9)
    Used as a component for the exhibit catalog for c/o The Velvet Underground, New York, NY
  - Portfolio with silkscreen prints for c/o The Velvet Underground, New York, NY, 2007 (Mapcase-folder 1)
    Includes 5 reproduction prints of Halloween Mod Happening, 4 of the Exploding Plastic Inevitable in Boston, and 1 of the Exploding Plastic Inevitable at RISD